Gianfranco Trotta

gian@giantrotta.dev | Lakewood, OH 44107 | 216-203-0303

<u>LinkedIn</u>: <u>GitHub</u>: <u>Portfolio</u>

Summary

Full-Stack Web Developer & Marketing Professional with over six years of background in the restaurant industry and customer service. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving skills to develop user-friendly, sophisticated websites and applications. Constantly learning and known to exemplify a strong work ethic. Adamant about achieving growth and success. Bilingual, fluent in English and Spanish.

Technical Skills

Computer and command line proficient. Coding proficiency in JavaScript, HTML, CSS. Experience using React, Node.Js, Express.Js, Firebase, SQL/noSQL databases, & working with RESTful APIs.

Projects

Outdoor Gear Bank — GitHub

 Outdoor Gear Bank is a full stack MERN application that provides a way for businesses to keep track of where their rental gear is at any state in the rental process. I was responsible for the authentication using Bcrypt with Passport.js and MongoDB, as well as the front end design and functionality for several components.

WildPlantID — GitLab

• WildPlantID is an iOS application developed for the Friends of Euclid Creek Watershed Program written in Objective C. Volunteering for CleGiveCamp I worked with a team to debug and update the UI of the existing application, which is used to identify plants within the Euclid Creek Watershed.

Comic-Verse — *GitHub*

Comic-Verse is a full stack website designed with Handlebars and Sequelize to be your one stop
destination for all comic book character information. During the development for this application I was
responsible for authentication using Bcrypt with Passport.js and mySQL, and back-end routing using Node
and Express.

LIRI — GitHub

• LIRI is a Language Interpretation and Recognition Interface designed to interpret user commands through the Terminal or Bash Window and generate requested data written in JavaScript using Node.is.

Cleveland Browns Trivia — GitHub

 A single-player Cleveland Browns themed trivia game that keeps track of your scores, gives you the ability to replay the game, and also displays GIF images based on correct or incorrect answers.

Gianfranco Trotta

gian@giantrotta.dev | Lakewood, OH 44107 | 216-203-0303

<u>LinkedIn</u> GitHub Portfolio

Experience

BioFlight VR, Akron, OH - Junior Developer

May. 2019 - Current

- Junior Software Developer working with web-based VR framework, A-Frame, in coordination with a film/graphics production team.
- Responsibilities include problem solving team-based and independent tasks, learning of new technologies, and general debugging.

Liquid Living, Twinsburg, OH — Marketing Manager

Nov. 2016 - Jan. 2018

- Conceptualized and orchestrated marketing campaigns that effectively reinforced and built the company brand.
- Displayed an ability to drive record-high marketing campaign response rates and executing successful product launches.

Flip Side, Cleveland, OH — General Manager

Sept. 2015 - Jan. 2018

- Supervised the preparation of meals and beverages ensuring compliance with all regulatory requirements and inspections.
- Ensured customer satisfaction and the proper management of inventory while also maintaining equipment supplies.
- Managed restaurant sales, labor, scheduling, training, and overall day to day operations.

Education

Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH — Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp

Full Stack Web Development Certification provided by Case Western Reserve University.

Cypress Bay High School, Weston, FL — Diploma

Early graduate and proud alumni of Cypress Bay High School.